# RICHARD MONFORT

135 North Pearl Street | Brockton, MA 02301

(774) 297-4742 | richard.s.monfort@gmail.com | rmonfort.github.io | www.linkedin.com/in/rmonfort

## SUMMARY

A self-taught software developer with over a year of professional experience. Interests and personal areas of study include web and .NET technologies such as HTML5, CSS3, JavaScript, C#, and ASP.NET Web Forms and MVC. Leverages both formal and informal training to provide software and hardware expertise.

## SKILLS

Languages – HTML5, CSS3, JavaScript, C#, SQL, Tcl, Expect
Frameworks and Libraries – ASP.NET Web Forms and MVC, jQuery
Operating Systems – Windows, Linux, Mac OS
Software – Visual Studio 2013
Hardware – PC hardware design and setup
Methodologies – Agile software development
General – Technical writing, analytical problem solving, working in teams, working independently

## KEY ACCOMPLISHMENTS

- ☑ Successfully delivered business process management solution to the client within the 6 month time frame
- ☑ Successfully built a fully functional device within a 4 month time frame on a 3 member team
- ☑ Identified and troubleshot various software and hardware issues in a timely manner reducing overall client downtime

#### PERSONAL PROJECTS

## **GitHub**

github.com/rmonfort

<u>Current Weather</u> (2015) – A web app that accept a US zip code and outputs the weather in the area. It implements the weather API from Wunderground. C#, ASP.NET MVC, JSON, AJAX

<u>Credit Card Validator</u> (2015) – A web app that validates Amex, Discover, Mastercard, and Visa card numbers. Implements the Luhn algorithm. C#, ASP.NET MVC

# **EDUCATION**

**BACHELOR OF SCIENCE IN COMPUTER ENGINEERING TECHNOLOGY** from Wentworth Institute of Technology (2007-2011), Boston, MA

- GPA: 3.32
- WIT Merit Award Scholarship, Dean's List Fall 2009
- Undergraduate Coursework: Technical Communications, Object-Oriented Programming with C++, Microcontrollers & Embedded Communications, Computer Systems Architecture,

Computer Communications & Networks, Computer Science I using C, Intro to Operating Systems

#### **PROJECTS**

**Automatic Window Blinds** (2011) - A device that opened and closed window blinds based on the temperature of the room and the amount of light outside. It used a single-board microcontroller in conjunction with a temperature sensor, a light sensor, and a rotary motor. Source code was written in C++.

- Resolved a motor overheating issue by adding sufficient delays to source code
- Successfully built a fully functional device within a 4 month time frame on a 3 member team

## PROFESSIONAL TRAINING

#### **BOOKS**

HTML and CSS - Design and Build Website, C++ Primer (5th Edition), Data Structures & Algorithms in C++ (2nd Edition), Think Like a Programmer: An Introduction to Creative Problem Solving, Clean Code - A Handbook of Agile Software Craftsmanship, Pro C# 5.0 and the .NET 4.5 Framework (6th Edition)

Pro ASP.NET MVC 5

#### **PLURALSIGHT**

C# Fundamentals with C# 5.0, Relational Database Design, HTML5 Fundamentals, HTML5 Advanced Topics, CSS3 In-Depth, JavaScript Fundamentals, Building Applications with ASP.NET MVC 4, ASP.NET MVC 4 Fundamentals, ASP.NET MVC 5 Fundamentals, Clean Code: Writing Code for Humans, Introduction to SQL, C# Generics, LINQ Fundamentals, HTTP Fundamentals, Introduction to ASP.NET 4 Web Forms

#### LYNDA

HTML Essential Training, CSS Fundamentals, JavaScript Essential Training, jQuery Essential Training, C# Essential Training, Up and Running with ASP.NET, ASP.NET MVC 5 Essential Training, SQL Essential Training

#### **EXPERIENCE**

**SOFTWARE DEVELOPER** – CABEM Technologies – Sep. 2015 to Present

• Developed and maintained web applications for clients using .NET technologies

**COMPUTER REPAIR TECHNICIAN** – Freelance – Dec. 2014 to Aug. 2015

Identified and troubleshot various software and hardware issues in the clients' PCs

WEB DEVELOPER (CONTRACT) - Harvard Business School - Oct. 2014 to Nov. 2014

- Created and maintained web forms for various courses using HTML5, CSS3, and JavaScript
- Trained coworkers in the use of Certain event management software
- Created and maintained documentation for Certain event management software so anyone could learn to use it

## **COMPUTER REPAIR TECHNICIAN** – Freelance – Oct. 2013 to Sep. 2014

Identified and troubleshot various software and hardware issues in the clients' PCs

## ASSOCIATE SOFTWARE ENGINEER - Accenture - Oct. 2012 to Sept. 2013

- Designed user interfaces for various projects based on client requirements using HTML5, CSS3, and PEGA PRPC
- Utilized various agile practices such as backlogs, user stories, and iterative and incremental development
- Trained new coworkers in user interface design using HTML5, CSS3, and PEGA PRPC
- Projects
  - Health Insurance (2012-2013) A business process management application that streamlines health insurance registration and maintenance.
     Role: UI Developer

Team: 14 members (3 frontend, 4 middleware, 4 backend, 3 project management)

- Resolved an issue involving lack of UI consistency by creating templates for regular use and encouraging coworkers to do the same
- Learned HTML5 and CSS3 in order to provide UI customizations requested by client
- Successfully delivered the product to the client within the 6 month time frame

# COMPUTER REPAIR TECHNICIAN - Freelance - Feb. 2012 to Sep. 2012

• Identified and troubleshot various software and hardware issues in the clients' PCs

## IT SERVICE DESK SUPPORT (CONTRACT) – Instron – Nov. 2011 to Jan. 2012

- Identified and troubleshot various software and hardware issues in a timely manner reducing overall client downtime
- Created and managed user accounts through active directory
- Maintained records of system changes and performed backups and file recovery
- Deployed services and systems using Symantec Ghost to fulfill needs of organization

## **IIT INTERN** – Museum of Science – Sept. 2010 to Dec. 2010

- Identified and troubleshot various software and hardware issues
- Created and managed user accounts through active directory

## **QA INTERN** – Tatara Systems – Jan. 2010 to Apr. 2010

- Developed various scripts using Tcl and Expect to increase efficiency of work place
- Organized and maintained various documentation